var words = 
[
    {
        "question": "فَلْيَأْتُوا",
        "answer": "Then let them bring",
        "pcklId": "255",
        "rootWordId": 12,
        "tlit": "falyatū",
        "frequency": 549,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 41,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " أَمْ لَهُمْ شُرَكَاءُ فَلْيَأْتُوا بِشُرَكَائِهِمْ إِنْ كَانُوا صَادِقِينَ",
        "rootWord": "أ ت ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَتَى",
        "waznEnglish": "to come, to bring",
        "waznTlit": "atā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 264,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "أَثِيمٍ",
        "answer": "sinful",
        "pcklId": "40",
        "rootWordId": 16,
        "tlit": "athīmin",
        "frequency": 48,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 12,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " مَنَّاعٍ لِلْخَيْرِ مُعْتَدٍ أَثِيمٍ",
        "rootWord": "أ ث م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَثِيم",
        "waznEnglish": "sinful",
        "waznTlit": "athīm",
        "waznType": "Adjective",
        "waznFreq": 7,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "لَأَجْرًا",
        "answer": "surely (is) a reward",
        "pcklId": "103",
        "rootWordId": 18,
        "tlit": "la-ajran",
        "frequency": 108,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 3,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " وَإِنَّ لَكَ لَأَجْرًا غَيْرَ مَمْنُونٍ",
        "rootWord": "أ ج ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَجْر",
        "waznEnglish": "reward, payment, dowry",
        "waznTlit": "ajr",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 105,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "أَجْرًا",
        "answer": "a payment",
        "pcklId": "104",
        "rootWordId": 18,
        "tlit": "ajran",
        "frequency": 108,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 46,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " أَمْ تَسْأَلُهُمْ أَجْرًا فَهُمْ مِنْ مَغْرَمٍ مُثْقَلُونَ",
        "rootWord": "أ ج ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَجْر",
        "waznEnglish": "reward, payment, dowry",
        "waznTlit": "ajr",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 105,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الْآخِرَةِ",
        "answer": "(of) the Hereafter",
        "pcklId": "219",
        "rootWordId": 22,
        "tlit": "l-ākhirati",
        "frequency": 250,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 33,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " كَذَٰلِكَ الْعَذَابُ وَلَعَذَابُ الْآخِرَةِ أَكْبَرُ لَوْ كَانُوا يَعْلَمُونَ",
        "rootWord": "أ خ ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "آخِر",
        "waznEnglish": "Hereafter, end, last, later generations",
        "waznTlit": "ākhir",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)",
        "waznFreq": 155,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "إِذْ",
        "answer": "when",
        "pcklId": "233",
        "rootWordId": 26,
        "tlit": "idh",
        "frequency": 239,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 17,
        "wordnum": 7,
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّا بَلَوْنَاهُمْ كَمَا بَلَوْنَا أَصْحَابَ الْجَنَّةِ إِذْ أَقْسَمُوا",
        "rootWord": "إِذ",
        "rootWordType": "time adverb",
        "wazn": "إِذ",
        "waznEnglish": "when",
        "waznTlit": "idh",
        "waznType": "Time adverb",
        "waznFreq": 239,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "إِذْ",
        "answer": "when",
        "pcklId": "234",
        "rootWordId": 26,
        "tlit": "idh",
        "frequency": 239,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 48,
        "wordnum": 8,
        "arabicAyah": " فَاصْبِرْ لِحُكْمِ رَبِّكَ وَلَا تَكُنْ كَصَاحِبِ الْحُوتِ إِذْ نَادَىٰ وَهُوَ مَكْظُومٌ",
        "rootWord": "إِذ",
        "rootWordType": "time adverb",
        "wazn": "إِذ",
        "waznEnglish": "when",
        "waznTlit": "idh",
        "waznType": "Time adverb",
        "waznFreq": 239,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "إِذَا",
        "answer": "When",
        "pcklId": "336",
        "rootWordId": 27,
        "tlit": "idhā",
        "frequency": 409,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 15,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " إِذَا تُتْلَىٰ عَلَيْهِ آيَاتُنَا قَالَ أَسَاطِيرُ الْأَوَّلِينَ",
        "rootWord": "إِذَا",
        "rootWordType": "nominal",
        "wazn": "إِذَا",
        "waznEnglish": "when",
        "waznTlit": "idhā",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Time adverb)",
        "waznFreq": 409,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "إِلَّا",
        "answer": "but",
        "pcklId": "535",
        "rootWordId": 58,
        "tlit": "illā",
        "frequency": 663,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 52,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " وَمَا هُوَ إِلَّا ذِكْرٌ لِلْعَالَمِينَ",
        "rootWord": "إِلَّا",
        "rootWordType": "particle",
        "wazn": "إِلَّا",
        "waznEnglish": "except",
        "waznTlit": "illā",
        "waznType": "Particle (Restriction particle)",
        "waznFreq": 663,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الَّذِينَ",
        "answer": "those who",
        "pcklId": "1380",
        "rootWordId": 59,
        "tlit": "alladhīna",
        "frequency": 1464,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 51,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " وَإِنْ يَكَادُ الَّذِينَ كَفَرُوا لَيُزْلِقُونَكَ بِأَبْصَارِهِمْ لَمَّا سَمِعُوا الذِّكْرَ",
        "rootWord": "ٱلَّذِى",
        "rootWordType": "nominal",
        "wazn": "ٱلَّذِى",
        "waznEnglish": "who, which, that",
        "waznTlit": "alladhī",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Relative pronoun)",
        "waznFreq": 1464,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "إِلَىٰ",
        "answer": "to",
        "pcklId": "703",
        "rootWordId": 63,
        "tlit": "ilā",
        "frequency": 742,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 32,
        "wordnum": 8,
        "arabicAyah": " عَسَىٰ رَبُّنَا أَنْ يُبْدِلَنَا خَيْرًا مِنْهَا إِنَّا إِلَىٰ رَبِّنَا رَاغِبُونَ",
        "rootWord": "إِلَىٰ",
        "rootWordType": "preposition",
        "wazn": "إِلَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to, toward, until",
        "waznTlit": "ilā",
        "waznType": "Preposition",
        "waznFreq": 742,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "إِلَىٰ",
        "answer": "to",
        "pcklId": "704",
        "rootWordId": 63,
        "tlit": "ilā",
        "frequency": 742,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 39,
        "wordnum": 6,
        "arabicAyah": " أَمْ لَكُمْ أَيْمَانٌ عَلَيْنَا بَالِغَةٌ إِلَىٰ يَوْمِ الْقِيَامَةِ إِنَّ لَكُمْ لَمَا تَحْكُمُونَ",
        "rootWord": "إِلَىٰ",
        "rootWordType": "preposition",
        "wazn": "إِلَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to, toward, until",
        "waznTlit": "ilā",
        "waznType": "Preposition",
        "waznFreq": 742,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "إِلَى",
        "answer": "to",
        "pcklId": "705",
        "rootWordId": 63,
        "tlit": "ilā",
        "frequency": 742,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 42,
        "wordnum": 6,
        "arabicAyah": " يَوْمَ يُكْشَفُ عَنْ سَاقٍ وَيُدْعَوْنَ إِلَى السُّجُودِ فَلَا يَسْتَطِيعُونَ",
        "rootWord": "إِلَىٰ",
        "rootWordType": "preposition",
        "wazn": "إِلَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to, toward, until",
        "waznTlit": "ilā",
        "waznType": "Preposition",
        "waznFreq": 742,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "إِلَى",
        "answer": "to",
        "pcklId": "706",
        "rootWordId": 63,
        "tlit": "ilā",
        "frequency": 742,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 43,
        "wordnum": 8,
        "arabicAyah": " وَقَدْ كَانُوا يُدْعَوْنَ إِلَى السُّجُودِ وَهُمْ سَالِمُونَ",
        "rootWord": "إِلَىٰ",
        "rootWordType": "preposition",
        "wazn": "إِلَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to, toward, until",
        "waznTlit": "ilā",
        "waznType": "Preposition",
        "waznFreq": 742,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "أَمْ",
        "answer": "Or",
        "pcklId": "129",
        "rootWordId": 66,
        "tlit": "am",
        "frequency": 137,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 37,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " أَمْ لَكُمْ كِتَابٌ فِيهِ تَدْرُسُونَ",
        "rootWord": "أَم",
        "rootWordType": "coordinating conjunction",
        "wazn": "أَم",
        "waznEnglish": "or",
        "waznTlit": "am",
        "waznType": "Coordinating conjunction",
        "waznFreq": 137,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "أَمْ",
        "answer": "Or",
        "pcklId": "130",
        "rootWordId": 66,
        "tlit": "am",
        "frequency": 137,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 39,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " أَمْ لَكُمْ أَيْمَانٌ عَلَيْنَا بَالِغَةٌ إِلَىٰ يَوْمِ الْقِيَامَةِ إِنَّ لَكُمْ لَمَا تَحْكُمُونَ",
        "rootWord": "أَم",
        "rootWordType": "coordinating conjunction",
        "wazn": "أَم",
        "waznEnglish": "or",
        "waznTlit": "am",
        "waznType": "Coordinating conjunction",
        "waznFreq": 137,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "أَمْ",
        "answer": "Or",
        "pcklId": "131",
        "rootWordId": 66,
        "tlit": "am",
        "frequency": 137,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 41,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " أَمْ لَهُمْ شُرَكَاءُ فَلْيَأْتُوا بِشُرَكَائِهِمْ إِنْ كَانُوا صَادِقِينَ",
        "rootWord": "أَم",
        "rootWordType": "coordinating conjunction",
        "wazn": "أَم",
        "waznEnglish": "or",
        "waznTlit": "am",
        "waznType": "Coordinating conjunction",
        "waznFreq": 137,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "أَمْ",
        "answer": "Or",
        "pcklId": "132",
        "rootWordId": 66,
        "tlit": "am",
        "frequency": 137,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 46,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " أَمْ تَسْأَلُهُمْ أَجْرًا فَهُمْ مِنْ مَغْرَمٍ مُثْقَلُونَ",
        "rootWord": "أَم",
        "rootWordType": "coordinating conjunction",
        "wazn": "أَم",
        "waznEnglish": "or",
        "waznTlit": "am",
        "waznType": "Coordinating conjunction",
        "waznFreq": 137,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "أَمْ",
        "answer": "Or",
        "pcklId": "133",
        "rootWordId": 66,
        "tlit": "am",
        "frequency": 137,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 47,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " أَمْ عِنْدَهُمُ الْغَيْبُ فَهُمْ يَكْتُبُونَ",
        "rootWord": "أَم",
        "rootWordType": "coordinating conjunction",
        "wazn": "أَم",
        "waznEnglish": "or",
        "waznTlit": "am",
        "waznType": "Coordinating conjunction",
        "waznFreq": 137,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الْأَوَّلِينَ",
        "answer": "(of) the former (people)",
        "pcklId": "54",
        "rootWordId": 85,
        "tlit": "l-awalīna",
        "frequency": 170,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 15,
        "wordnum": 7,
        "arabicAyah": " إِذَا تُتْلَىٰ عَلَيْهِ آيَاتُنَا قَالَ أَسَاطِيرُ الْأَوَّلِينَ",
        "rootWord": "أ و ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَوَّل",
        "waznEnglish": "(the) first",
        "waznTlit": "awwal",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)",
        "waznFreq": 82,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "آيَاتُنَا",
        "answer": "Our Verses",
        "pcklId": "376",
        "rootWordId": 90,
        "tlit": "āyātunā",
        "frequency": 382,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 15,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " إِذَا تُتْلَىٰ عَلَيْهِ آيَاتُنَا قَالَ أَسَاطِيرُ الْأَوَّلِينَ",
        "rootWord": "أ ي ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أ ي ي",
        "waznEnglish": "Our Signs",
        "waznTlit": "hamza yā yā",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 382,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "يُبْدِلَنَا",
        "answer": "will substitute for us",
        "pcklId": "25",
        "rootWordId": 106,
        "tlit": "yub'dilanā",
        "frequency": 44,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 32,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " عَسَىٰ رَبُّنَا أَنْ يُبْدِلَنَا خَيْرًا مِنْهَا إِنَّا إِلَىٰ رَبِّنَا رَاغِبُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ب د ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "يُبْدِلَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to substitute",
        "waznTlit": "yub'dila",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)",
        "waznFreq": 3,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "فَسَتُبْصِرُ",
        "answer": "So you will see",
        "pcklId": "29",
        "rootWordId": 129,
        "tlit": "fasatub'ṣiru",
        "frequency": 148,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 5,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " فَسَتُبْصِرُ وَيُبْصِرُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ب ص ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَبْصَرَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to see",
        "waznTlit": "abṣara",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)",
        "waznFreq": 29,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "وَيُبْصِرُونَ",
        "answer": "and they will see",
        "pcklId": "30",
        "rootWordId": 129,
        "tlit": "wayub'ṣirūna",
        "frequency": 148,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 5,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " فَسَتُبْصِرُ وَيُبْصِرُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ب ص ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَبْصَرَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to see",
        "waznTlit": "abṣara",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)",
        "waznFreq": 29,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "أَبْصَارُهُمْ",
        "answer": "their eyes",
        "pcklId": "76",
        "rootWordId": 129,
        "tlit": "abṣāruhum",
        "frequency": 148,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 43,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " خَاشِعَةً أَبْصَارُهُمْ تَرْهَقُهُمْ ذِلَّةٌ",
        "rootWord": "ب ص ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "بَصَر",
        "waznEnglish": "I perceived",
        "waznTlit": "baṣar",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 48,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "بِأَبْصَارِهِمْ",
        "answer": "with their look",
        "pcklId": "77",
        "rootWordId": 129,
        "tlit": "bi-abṣārihim",
        "frequency": 148,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 51,
        "wordnum": 6,
        "arabicAyah": " وَإِنْ يَكَادُ الَّذِينَ كَفَرُوا لَيُزْلِقُونَكَ بِأَبْصَارِهِمْ",
        "rootWord": "ب ص ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "بَصَر",
        "waznEnglish": "I perceived",
        "waznTlit": "baṣar",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 48,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "بَعْدَ",
        "answer": "after",
        "pcklId": "205",
        "rootWordId": 139,
        "tlit": "baʿda",
        "frequency": 235,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 13,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " عُتُلٍّ بَعْدَ ذَٰلِكَ زَنِيمٍ",
        "rootWord": "ب ع د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "بَعْد",
        "waznEnglish": "was long",
        "waznTlit": "baʿd",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Time adverb)",
        "waznFreq": 199,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "بَعْضُهُمْ",
        "answer": "some of them",
        "pcklId": "154",
        "rootWordId": 141,
        "tlit": "baʿḍuhum",
        "frequency": 158,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 30,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " فَأَقْبَلَ بَعْضُهُمْ عَلَىٰ بَعْضٍ يَتَلَاوَمُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ب ع ض",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "بَعْض",
        "waznEnglish": "some of you",
        "waznTlit": "baʿḍ",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 157,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "بَعْضٍ",
        "answer": "others",
        "pcklId": "155",
        "rootWordId": 141,
        "tlit": "baʿḍin",
        "frequency": 158,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 30,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " فَأَقْبَلَ بَعْضُهُمْ عَلَىٰ بَعْضٍ يَتَلَاوَمُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ب ع ض",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "بَعْض",
        "waznEnglish": "some of you",
        "waznTlit": "baʿḍ",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 157,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "بَالِغَةٌ",
        "answer": "reaching",
        "pcklId": "75",
        "rootWordId": 157,
        "tlit": "bālighatun",
        "frequency": 77,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 39,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " أَمْ لَكُمْ أَيْمَانٌ عَلَيْنَا بَالِغَةٌ إِلَىٰ يَوْمِ الْقِيَامَةِ إِنَّ لَكُمْ لَمَا تَحْكُمُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ب ل غ",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "بَٰلِغَة",
        "waznEnglish": "reaches",
        "waznTlit": "bālighat",
        "waznType": "Active participle (Adjective)",
        "waznFreq": 3,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "بَلَوْنَاهُمْ",
        "answer": "have tried them",
        "pcklId": "17",
        "rootWordId": 158,
        "tlit": "balawnāhum",
        "frequency": 38,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 17,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّا بَلَوْنَاهُمْ كَمَا بَلَوْنَا أَصْحَابَ الْجَنَّةِ إِذْ أَقْسَمُوا",
        "rootWord": "ب ل و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "بَلَوْ",
        "waznEnglish": "to test",
        "waznTlit": "balaw",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 20,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "بَلَوْنَا",
        "answer": "We tried",
        "pcklId": "18",
        "rootWordId": 158,
        "tlit": "balawnā",
        "frequency": 38,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 17,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّا بَلَوْنَاهُمْ كَمَا بَلَوْنَا أَصْحَابَ الْجَنَّةِ إِذْ أَقْسَمُوا",
        "rootWord": "ب ل و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "بَلَوْ",
        "waznEnglish": "to test",
        "waznTlit": "balaw",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 20,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "وَبَنِينَ",
        "answer": "and children",
        "pcklId": "171",
        "rootWordId": 160,
        "tlit": "wabanīna",
        "frequency": 184,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 14,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " أَنْ كَانَ ذَا مَالٍ وَبَنِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ب ن ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "بُنَىّ",
        "waznEnglish": "they built",
        "waznTlit": "buna",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 80,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "تُتْلَىٰ",
        "answer": "are recited",
        "pcklId": "57",
        "rootWordId": 188,
        "tlit": "tut'lā",
        "frequency": 63,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 15,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " إِذَا تُتْلَىٰ عَلَيْهِ آيَاتُنَا قَالَ أَسَاطِيرُ الْأَوَّلِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ت ل و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "تَلَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to recite",
        "waznTlit": "talā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 61,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "مُثْقَلُونَ",
        "answer": "(are) burdened",
        "pcklId": "26",
        "rootWordId": 205,
        "tlit": "muth'qalūna",
        "frequency": 28,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 46,
        "wordnum": 7,
        "arabicAyah": " أَمْ تَسْأَلُهُمْ أَجْرًا فَهُمْ مِنْ مَغْرَمٍ مُثْقَلُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ث ق ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُّثْقَلُون",
        "waznEnglish": "(will be) heavy",
        "waznTlit": "muth'qalūn",
        "waznType": "Passive participle (form IV)",
        "waznFreq": 2,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "يَسْتَثْنُونَ",
        "answer": "making exception",
        "pcklId": "1",
        "rootWordId": 210,
        "tlit": "yastathnūna",
        "frequency": 29,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 18,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَا يَسْتَثْنُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ث ن ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "يَسْتَثْنُ",
        "waznEnglish": "to except",
        "waznTlit": "yastathnu",
        "waznType": "Verb (form X)",
        "waznFreq": 1,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "فَاجْتَبَاهُ",
        "answer": "But chose him",
        "pcklId": "10",
        "rootWordId": 222,
        "tlit": "fa-ij'tabāhu",
        "frequency": 12,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 50,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " فَاجْتَبَاهُ رَبُّهُ فَجَعَلَهُ مِنَ الصَّالِحِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ج ب ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ٱجْتَبَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to choose",
        "waznTlit": "ij'tabā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form VIII)",
        "waznFreq": 10,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "كَالْمُجْرِمِينَ",
        "answer": "like the criminals",
        "pcklId": "53",
        "rootWordId": 241,
        "tlit": "kal-muj'rimīna",
        "frequency": 66,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 35,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " أَفَنَجْعَلُ الْمُسْلِمِينَ كَالْمُجْرِمِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ج ر م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُجْرِم",
        "waznEnglish": "incite you",
        "waznTlit": "muj'rim",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form IV) (Noun)",
        "waznFreq": 52,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "أَفَنَجْعَلُ",
        "answer": "Then will We treat",
        "pcklId": "312",
        "rootWordId": 249,
        "tlit": "afanajʿalu",
        "frequency": 346,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 35,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " أَفَنَجْعَلُ الْمُسْلِمِينَ كَالْمُجْرِمِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ج ع ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "جَعَلَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to make",
        "waznTlit": "jaʿala",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 340,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "فَجَعَلَهُ",
        "answer": "and made him",
        "pcklId": "313",
        "rootWordId": 249,
        "tlit": "fajaʿalahu",
        "frequency": 346,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 50,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " فَاجْتَبَاهُ رَبُّهُ فَجَعَلَهُ مِنَ الصَّالِحِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ج ع ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "جَعَلَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to make",
        "waznTlit": "jaʿala",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 340,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الْجَنَّةِ",
        "answer": "(of) the garden",
        "pcklId": "117",
        "rootWordId": 267,
        "tlit": "l-janati",
        "frequency": 201,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 17,
        "wordnum": 6,
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّا بَلَوْنَاهُمْ كَمَا بَلَوْنَا أَصْحَابَ الْجَنَّةِ",
        "rootWord": "ج ن ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "جَنَّة",
        "waznEnglish": "covered",
        "waznTlit": "jannat",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)",
        "waznFreq": 147,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "جَنَّاتِ",
        "answer": "(are) Gardens",
        "pcklId": "118",
        "rootWordId": 267,
        "tlit": "jannāti",
        "frequency": 201,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 34,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّ لِلْمُتَّقِينَ عِنْدَ رَبِّهِمْ جَنَّاتِ النَّعِيمِ",
        "rootWord": "ج ن ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "جَنَّة",
        "waznEnglish": "covered",
        "waznTlit": "jannat",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)",
        "waznFreq": 147,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "بِمَجْنُونٍ",
        "answer": "a madman",
        "pcklId": "198",
        "rootWordId": 267,
        "tlit": "bimajnūnin",
        "frequency": 201,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 2,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " مَا أَنْتَ بِنِعْمَةِ رَبِّكَ بِمَجْنُونٍ",
        "rootWord": "ج ن ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَجْنُون",
        "waznEnglish": "covered",
        "waznTlit": "majnūn",
        "waznType": "Passive participle",
        "waznFreq": 11,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "لَمَجْنُونٌ",
        "answer": "(is) surely mad",
        "pcklId": "199",
        "rootWordId": 267,
        "tlit": "lamajnūnun",
        "frequency": 201,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 51,
        "wordnum": 12,
        "arabicAyah": " وَيَقُولُونَ إِنَّهُ لَمَجْنُونٌ",
        "rootWord": "ج ن ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَجْنُون",
        "waznEnglish": "covered",
        "waznTlit": "majnūn",
        "waznType": "Passive participle",
        "waznFreq": 11,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الْحَدِيثِ",
        "answer": "Statement",
        "pcklId": "29",
        "rootWordId": 297,
        "tlit": "l-ḥadīthi",
        "frequency": 36,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 44,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " فَذَرْنِي وَمَنْ يُكَذِّبُ بِهَٰذَا الْحَدِيثِ",
        "rootWord": "ح د ث",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "حَدِيث",
        "waznEnglish": "Do you tell them",
        "waznTlit": "ḥadīth",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 28,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "حَرْثِكُمْ",
        "answer": "your crop",
        "pcklId": "13",
        "rootWordId": 302,
        "tlit": "ḥarthikum",
        "frequency": 14,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 22,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " أَنِ اغْدُوا عَلَىٰ حَرْثِكُمْ إِنْ كُنْتُمْ صَارِمِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ح ر ث",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "حَرْث",
        "waznEnglish": "you sow",
        "waznTlit": "ḥarth",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 13,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "حَرْدٍ",
        "answer": "determination",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 304,
        "tlit": "ḥardin",
        "frequency": 1,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 25,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " وَغَدَوْا عَلَىٰ حَرْدٍ قَادِرِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ح ر د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ح ر د",
        "waznEnglish": "determination",
        "waznTlit": "ḥā rā dāl",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 1,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "مَحْرُومُونَ",
        "answer": "(are) deprived",
        "pcklId": "76",
        "rootWordId": 312,
        "tlit": "maḥrūmūna",
        "frequency": 83,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 27,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " بَلْ نَحْنُ مَحْرُومُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ح ر م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَحْرُوم",
        "waznEnglish": "He has forbidden",
        "waznTlit": "maḥrūm",
        "waznType": "Passive participle",
        "waznFreq": 4,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "تَحْكُمُونَ",
        "answer": "(do) you judge",
        "pcklId": "43",
        "rootWordId": 345,
        "tlit": "taḥkumūna",
        "frequency": 210,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 36,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " مَا لَكُمْ كَيْفَ تَحْكُمُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ح ك م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "حَكَمَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to judge",
        "waznTlit": "ḥakama",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 45,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "تَحْكُمُونَ",
        "answer": "you judge",
        "pcklId": "44",
        "rootWordId": 345,
        "tlit": "taḥkumūna",
        "frequency": 210,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 39,
        "wordnum": 12,
        "arabicAyah": " أَمْ لَكُمْ أَيْمَانٌ عَلَيْنَا بَالِغَةٌ إِلَىٰ يَوْمِ الْقِيَامَةِ إِنَّ لَكُمْ لَمَا تَحْكُمُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ح ك م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "حَكَمَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to judge",
        "waznTlit": "ḥakama",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 45,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "لِحُكْمِ",
        "answer": "for (the) decision",
        "pcklId": "83",
        "rootWordId": 345,
        "tlit": "liḥuk'mi",
        "frequency": 210,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 48,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " فَاصْبِرْ لِحُكْمِ رَبِّكَ وَلَا تَكُنْ كَصَاحِبِ الْحُوتِ",
        "rootWord": "ح ك م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "حُكْم",
        "waznEnglish": "will judge",
        "waznTlit": "ḥuk'm",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 30,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "حَلَّافٍ",
        "answer": "habitual swearer",
        "pcklId": "12",
        "rootWordId": 346,
        "tlit": "ḥallāfin",
        "frequency": 13,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 10,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَا تُطِعْ كُلَّ حَلَّافٍ مَهِينٍ",
        "rootWord": "ح ل ف",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "حَلَّاف",
        "waznEnglish": "swearing",
        "waznTlit": "ḥallāf",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 1,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الْحُوتِ",
        "answer": "(of) the fish",
        "pcklId": "4",
        "rootWordId": 364,
        "tlit": "l-ḥūti",
        "frequency": 5,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 48,
        "wordnum": 7,
        "arabicAyah": " فَاصْبِرْ لِحُكْمِ رَبِّكَ وَلَا تَكُنْ كَصَاحِبِ الْحُوتِ إِذْ نَادَىٰ وَهُوَ مَكْظُومٌ",
        "rootWord": "ح و ت",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ح و ت",
        "waznEnglish": "their fish",
        "waznTlit": "ḥā wāw tā",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 5,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "حَيْثُ",
        "answer": "where",
        "pcklId": "15",
        "rootWordId": 373,
        "tlit": "ḥaythu",
        "frequency": 31,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 44,
        "wordnum": 8,
        "arabicAyah": " سَنَسْتَدْرِجُهُمْ مِنْ حَيْثُ لَا يَعْلَمُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ح ي ث",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "حَيْث",
        "waznEnglish": "wherever",
        "waznTlit": "ḥayth",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)",
        "waznFreq": 29,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الْخُرْطُومِ",
        "answer": "the snout",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 401,
        "tlit": "l-khur'ṭūmi",
        "frequency": 1,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 16,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " سَنَسِمُهُ عَلَى الْخُرْطُومِ",
        "rootWord": "خ ر ط م",
        "rootWordType": "quadriliteral root",
        "wazn": "خ ر ط م",
        "waznEnglish": "the snout",
        "waznTlit": "khā rā ṭā mīm",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 1,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "خَاشِعَةً",
        "answer": "Humbled",
        "pcklId": "13",
        "rootWordId": 409,
        "tlit": "khāshiʿatan",
        "frequency": 17,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 43,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " خَاشِعَةً أَبْصَارُهُمْ تَرْهَقُهُمْ ذِلَّةٌ",
        "rootWord": "خ ش ع",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "خَاشِع",
        "waznEnglish": "And (will be) humbled",
        "waznTlit": "khāshiʿ",
        "waznType": "Active participle",
        "waznFreq": 14,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "يَتَخَافَتُونَ",
        "answer": "lowered (their) voices",
        "pcklId": "2",
        "rootWordId": 422,
        "tlit": "yatakhāfatūna",
        "frequency": 3,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 23,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " فَانْطَلَقُوا وَهُمْ يَتَخَافَتُونَ",
        "rootWord": "خ ف ت",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "يَتَخَٰفَتُ",
        "waznEnglish": "to murmur",
        "waznTlit": "yatakhāfatu",
        "waznType": "Verb (form VI)",
        "waznFreq": 2,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "خُلُقٍ",
        "answer": "(of) a moral character",
        "pcklId": "245",
        "rootWordId": 431,
        "tlit": "khuluqin",
        "frequency": 261,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 4,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " وَإِنَّكَ لَعَلَىٰ خُلُقٍ عَظِيمٍ",
        "rootWord": "خ ل ق",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "خُلُق",
        "waznEnglish": "created you",
        "waznTlit": "khuluq",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 2,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "تَخَيَّرُونَ",
        "answer": "you choose",
        "pcklId": "1",
        "rootWordId": 449,
        "tlit": "takhayyarūna",
        "frequency": 196,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 38,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّ لَكُمْ فِيهِ لَمَا تَخَيَّرُونَ",
        "rootWord": "خ ي ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "يَتَخَيَّرُ",
        "waznEnglish": "to select, to choose",
        "waznTlit": "yatakhayyaru",
        "waznType": "Verb (form V)",
        "waznFreq": 2,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "لِلْخَيْرِ",
        "answer": "of (the) good",
        "pcklId": "142",
        "rootWordId": 449,
        "tlit": "lil'khayri",
        "frequency": 196,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 12,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " مَنَّاعٍ لِلْخَيْرِ مُعْتَدٍ أَثِيمٍ",
        "rootWord": "خ ي ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "خَيْر",
        "waznEnglish": "they select",
        "waznTlit": "khayr",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)",
        "waznFreq": 178,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "خَيْرًا",
        "answer": "a better",
        "pcklId": "143",
        "rootWordId": 449,
        "tlit": "khayran",
        "frequency": 196,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 32,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " عَسَىٰ رَبُّنَا أَنْ يُبْدِلَنَا خَيْرًا مِنْهَا إِنَّا إِلَىٰ رَبِّنَا رَاغِبُونَ",
        "rootWord": "خ ي ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "خَيْر",
        "waznEnglish": "they select",
        "waznTlit": "khayr",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)",
        "waznFreq": 178,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "يَدْخُلَنَّهَا",
        "answer": "will enter it",
        "pcklId": "71",
        "rootWordId": 461,
        "tlit": "yadkhulannahā",
        "frequency": 126,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 24,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " أَنْ لَا يَدْخُلَنَّهَا الْيَوْمَ عَلَيْكُمْ مِسْكِينٌ",
        "rootWord": "د خ ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "دَخَلَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to enter",
        "waznTlit": "dakhala",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 76,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "سَنَسْتَدْرِجُهُمْ",
        "answer": "We will progressively lead them",
        "pcklId": "1",
        "rootWordId": 464,
        "tlit": "sanastadrijuhum",
        "frequency": 20,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 44,
        "wordnum": 6,
        "arabicAyah": " فَذَرْنِي وَمَنْ يُكَذِّبُ بِهَٰذَا الْحَدِيثِ سَنَسْتَدْرِجُهُمْ مِنْ حَيْثُ لَا يَعْلَمُونَ",
        "rootWord": "د ر ج",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نَسْتَدْرِجُ",
        "waznEnglish": "to gradually lead",
        "waznTlit": "nastadriju",
        "waznType": "Verb (form X)",
        "waznFreq": 2,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "تَدْرُسُونَ",
        "answer": "you learn",
        "pcklId": "4",
        "rootWordId": 466,
        "tlit": "tadrusūna",
        "frequency": 6,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 37,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " أَمْ لَكُمْ كِتَابٌ فِيهِ تَدْرُسُونَ",
        "rootWord": "د ر س",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "دَرَسُ",
        "waznEnglish": "to study, to learn",
        "waznTlit": "darasu",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 5,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "تَدَارَكَهُ",
        "answer": "overtook him",
        "pcklId": "8",
        "rootWordId": 467,
        "tlit": "tadārakahu",
        "frequency": 12,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 49,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " لَوْلَا أَنْ تَدَارَكَهُ نِعْمَةٌ مِنْ رَبِّهِ لَنُبِذَ بِالْعَرَاءِ وَهُوَ مَذْمُومٌ",
        "rootWord": "د ر ك",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ٱدَّٰرَكَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to overtake, to arrest",
        "waznTlit": "iddāraka",
        "waznType": "Verb (form VI)",
        "waznFreq": 3,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "وَيُدْعَوْنَ",
        "answer": "and they will be called",
        "pcklId": "158",
        "rootWordId": 474,
        "tlit": "wayud'ʿawna",
        "frequency": 212,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 42,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " يَوْمَ يُكْشَفُ عَنْ سَاقٍ وَيُدْعَوْنَ إِلَى السُّجُودِ فَلَا يَسْتَطِيعُونَ",
        "rootWord": "د ع و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "دَعَا",
        "waznEnglish": "to call, to invite, to pray",
        "waznTlit": "daʿā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 170,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "يُدْعَوْنَ",
        "answer": "called",
        "pcklId": "159",
        "rootWordId": 474,
        "tlit": "yud'ʿawna",
        "frequency": 212,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 43,
        "wordnum": 7,
        "arabicAyah": " وَقَدْ كَانُوا يُدْعَوْنَ إِلَى السُّجُودِ وَهُمْ سَالِمُونَ",
        "rootWord": "د ع و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "دَعَا",
        "waznEnglish": "to call, to invite, to pray",
        "waznTlit": "daʿā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 170,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "تُدْهِنُ",
        "answer": "you should compromise",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 492,
        "tlit": "tud'hinu",
        "frequency": 5,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 9,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " وَدُّوا لَوْ تُدْهِنُ",
        "rootWord": "د ه ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "يُدْهِنُ",
        "waznEnglish": "to compromise",
        "waznTlit": "yud'hinu",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)",
        "waznFreq": 2,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "فَيُدْهِنُونَ",
        "answer": "so they would compromise",
        "pcklId": "1",
        "rootWordId": 492,
        "tlit": "fayud'hinūna",
        "frequency": 5,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 9,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " فَيُدْهِنُونَ",
        "rootWord": "د ه ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "يُدْهِنُ",
        "waznEnglish": "to compromise",
        "waznTlit": "yud'hinu",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)",
        "waznFreq": 2,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الذِّكْرَ",
        "answer": "the Message",
        "pcklId": "266",
        "rootWordId": 511,
        "tlit": "l-dhik'ra",
        "frequency": 292,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 51,
        "wordnum": 9,
        "arabicAyah": " وَإِنْ يَكَادُ الَّذِينَ كَفَرُوا لَيُزْلِقُونَكَ بِأَبْصَارِهِمْ لَمَّا سَمِعُوا الذِّكْرَ",
        "rootWord": "ذ ك ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ذِكْر",
        "waznEnglish": "Remember",
        "waznTlit": "dhik'r",
        "waznType": "Verbal noun",
        "waznFreq": 76,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "ذِكْرٌ",
        "answer": "a Reminder",
        "pcklId": "267",
        "rootWordId": 511,
        "tlit": "dhik'run",
        "frequency": 292,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 52,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " وَمَا هُوَ إِلَّا ذِكْرٌ لِلْعَالَمِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ذ ك ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ذِكْر",
        "waznEnglish": "Remember",
        "waznTlit": "dhik'r",
        "waznType": "Verbal noun",
        "waznFreq": 76,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "ذِلَّةٌ",
        "answer": "humiliation",
        "pcklId": "21",
        "rootWordId": 513,
        "tlit": "dhillatun",
        "frequency": 24,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 43,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " خَاشِعَةً أَبْصَارُهُمْ تَرْهَقُهُمْ ذِلَّةٌ وَقَدْ كَانُوا يُدْعَوْنَ إِلَى السُّجُودِ وَهُمْ سَالِمُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ذ ل ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ذِلَّة",
        "waznEnglish": "we were humiliated",
        "waznTlit": "dhillat",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 7,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "مَذْمُومٌ",
        "answer": "(was) blamed",
        "pcklId": "4",
        "rootWordId": 514,
        "tlit": "madhmūmun",
        "frequency": 5,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 49,
        "wordnum": 10,
        "arabicAyah": " لَوْلَا أَنْ تَدَارَكَهُ نِعْمَةٌ مِنْ رَبِّهِ لَنُبِذَ بِالْعَرَاءِ وَهُوَ مَذْمُومٌ",
        "rootWord": "ذ م م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَذْمُوم",
        "waznEnglish": "covenant of protection",
        "waznTlit": "madhmūm",
        "waznType": "Passive participle",
        "waznFreq": 3,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "رَأَوْهَا",
        "answer": "they saw it",
        "pcklId": "241",
        "rootWordId": 523,
        "tlit": "ra-awhā",
        "frequency": 328,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 26,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " فَلَمَّا رَأَوْهَا قَالُوا إِنَّا لَضَالُّونَ",
        "rootWord": "ر أ ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَءَا",
        "waznEnglish": "to see",
        "waznTlit": "raā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 271,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "رَبِّكَ",
        "answer": "(of) your Lord",
        "pcklId": "882",
        "rootWordId": 524,
        "tlit": "rabbika",
        "frequency": 980,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 2,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " مَا أَنْتَ بِنِعْمَةِ رَبِّكَ بِمَجْنُونٍ",
        "rootWord": "ر ب ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَبّ",
        "waznEnglish": "the Lord",
        "waznTlit": "rabb",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 975,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "رَبَّكَ",
        "answer": "your Lord",
        "pcklId": "883",
        "rootWordId": 524,
        "tlit": "rabbaka",
        "frequency": 980,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 7,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّ رَبَّكَ هُوَ أَعْلَمُ بِمَنْ ضَلَّ عَنْ سَبِيلِهِ وَهُوَ أَعْلَمُ بِالْمُهْتَدِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ر ب ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَبّ",
        "waznEnglish": "the Lord",
        "waznTlit": "rabb",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 975,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "رَبِّكَ",
        "answer": "your Lord",
        "pcklId": "884",
        "rootWordId": 524,
        "tlit": "rabbika",
        "frequency": 980,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 19,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " فَطَافَ عَلَيْهَا طَائِفٌ مِنْ رَبِّكَ وَهُمْ نَائِمُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ر ب ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَبّ",
        "waznEnglish": "the Lord",
        "waznTlit": "rabb",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 975,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "رَبِّنَا",
        "answer": "(to) our Lord",
        "pcklId": "885",
        "rootWordId": 524,
        "tlit": "rabbinā",
        "frequency": 980,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 29,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " قَالُوا سُبْحَانَ رَبِّنَا إِنَّا كُنَّا ظَالِمِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ر ب ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَبّ",
        "waznEnglish": "the Lord",
        "waznTlit": "rabb",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 975,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "رَبُّنَا",
        "answer": "our Lord",
        "pcklId": "886",
        "rootWordId": 524,
        "tlit": "rabbunā",
        "frequency": 980,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 32,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " عَسَىٰ رَبُّنَا أَنْ يُبْدِلَنَا خَيْرًا مِنْهَا",
        "rootWord": "ر ب ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَبّ",
        "waznEnglish": "the Lord",
        "waznTlit": "rabb",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 975,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "رَبِّنَا",
        "answer": "our Lord",
        "pcklId": "887",
        "rootWordId": 524,
        "tlit": "rabbinā",
        "frequency": 980,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 32,
        "wordnum": 9,
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّا إِلَىٰ رَبِّنَا رَاغِبُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ر ب ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَبّ",
        "waznEnglish": "the Lord",
        "waznTlit": "rabb",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 975,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "رَبِّهِمْ",
        "answer": "their Lord",
        "pcklId": "888",
        "rootWordId": 524,
        "tlit": "rabbihim",
        "frequency": 980,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 34,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّ لِلْمُتَّقِينَ عِنْدَ رَبِّهِمْ جَنَّاتِ النَّعِيمِ",
        "rootWord": "ر ب ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَبّ",
        "waznEnglish": "the Lord",
        "waznTlit": "rabb",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 975,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "رَبِّكَ",
        "answer": "(of) your Lord",
        "pcklId": "889",
        "rootWordId": 524,
        "tlit": "rabbika",
        "frequency": 980,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 48,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " فَاصْبِرْ لِحُكْمِ رَبِّكَ وَلَا تَكُنْ كَصَاحِبِ الْحُوتِ إِذْ نَادَىٰ وَهُوَ مَكْظُومٌ",
        "rootWord": "ر ب ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَبّ",
        "waznEnglish": "the Lord",
        "waznTlit": "rabb",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 975,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "رَبِّهِ",
        "answer": "his Lord",
        "pcklId": "890",
        "rootWordId": 524,
        "tlit": "rabbihi",
        "frequency": 980,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 49,
        "wordnum": 6,
        "arabicAyah": " لَوْلَا أَنْ تَدَارَكَهُ نِعْمَةٌ مِنْ رَبِّهِ لَنُبِذَ بِالْعَرَاءِ وَهُوَ مَذْمُومٌ",
        "rootWord": "ر ب ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَبّ",
        "waznEnglish": "the Lord",
        "waznTlit": "rabb",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 975,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "رَبُّهُ",
        "answer": "his Lord",
        "pcklId": "891",
        "rootWordId": 524,
        "tlit": "rabbuhu",
        "frequency": 980,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 50,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " فَاجْتَبَاهُ رَبُّهُ فَجَعَلَهُ مِنَ الصَّالِحِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ر ب ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَبّ",
        "waznEnglish": "the Lord",
        "waznTlit": "rabb",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 975,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "رَاغِبُونَ",
        "answer": "turn devoutly",
        "pcklId": "7",
        "rootWordId": 566,
        "tlit": "rāghibūna",
        "frequency": 8,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 32,
        "wordnum": 10,
        "arabicAyah": " عَسَىٰ رَبُّنَا أَنْ يُبْدِلَنَا خَيْرًا مِنْهَا إِنَّا إِلَىٰ رَبِّنَا رَاغِبُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ر غ ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَاغِب",
        "waznEnglish": "will turn away",
        "waznTlit": "rāghib",
        "waznType": "Active participle",
        "waznFreq": 3,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "تَرْهَقُهُمْ",
        "answer": "will cover them",
        "pcklId": "2",
        "rootWordId": 596,
        "tlit": "tarhaquhum",
        "frequency": 10,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 43,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " خَاشِعَةً أَبْصَارُهُمْ تَرْهَقُهُمْ ذِلَّةٌ وَقَدْ كَانُوا يُدْعَوْنَ إِلَى السُّجُودِ",
        "rootWord": "ر ه ق",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "يَرْهَقُ",
        "waznEnglish": "to cover",
        "waznTlit": "yarhaqu",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 5,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "زَعِيمٌ",
        "answer": "(is) responsible",
        "pcklId": "16",
        "rootWordId": 620,
        "tlit": "zaʿīmun",
        "frequency": 17,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 40,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " سَلْهُمْ أَيُّهُمْ بِذَٰلِكَ زَعِيمٌ",
        "rootWord": "ز ع م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "زَعِيم",
        "waznEnglish": "claim",
        "waznTlit": "zaʿīm",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 2,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "لَيُزْلِقُونَكَ",
        "answer": "surely make you slip",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 627,
        "tlit": "layuz'liqūnaka",
        "frequency": 2,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 51,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " وَإِنْ يَكَادُ الَّذِينَ كَفَرُوا لَيُزْلِقُونَكَ بِأَبْصَارِهِمْ لَمَّا سَمِعُوا الذِّكْرَ",
        "rootWord": "ز ل ق",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "يُزْلِقُ",
        "waznEnglish": "to make slip",
        "waznTlit": "yuz'liqu",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)",
        "waznFreq": 1,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "زَنِيمٍ",
        "answer": "utterly useless",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 633,
        "tlit": "zanīmin",
        "frequency": 1,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 13,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " عُتُلٍّ بَعْدَ ذَٰلِكَ زَنِيمٍ",
        "rootWord": "ز ن م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ز ن م",
        "waznEnglish": "utterly useless",
        "waznTlit": "zāy nūn mīm",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 1,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "سَلْهُمْ",
        "answer": "Ask them",
        "pcklId": "98",
        "rootWordId": 647,
        "tlit": "salhum",
        "frequency": 129,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 40,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " سَلْهُمْ أَيُّهُمْ بِذَٰلِكَ زَعِيمٌ",
        "rootWord": "س أ ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "سَأَلَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to ask",
        "waznTlit": "sa-ala",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 106,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "تَسْأَلُهُمْ",
        "answer": "you ask them",
        "pcklId": "99",
        "rootWordId": 647,
        "tlit": "tasaluhum",
        "frequency": 129,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 46,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " أَمْ تَسْأَلُهُمْ أَجْرًا فَهُمْ مِنْ مَغْرَمٍ مُثْقَلُونَ",
        "rootWord": "س أ ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "سَأَلَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to ask",
        "waznTlit": "sa-ala",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 106,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "تُسَبِّحُونَ",
        "answer": "you glorify (Allah)? ",
        "pcklId": "39",
        "rootWordId": 651,
        "tlit": "tusabbiḥūna",
        "frequency": 92,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 28,
        "wordnum": 7,
        "arabicAyah": " قَالَ أَوْسَطُهُمْ أَلَمْ أَقُلْ لَكُمْ لَوْلَا تُسَبِّحُونَ",
        "rootWord": "س ب ح",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "سَبَّحَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to glorify, to praise",
        "waznTlit": "sabbaḥa",
        "waznType": "Verb (form II)",
        "waznFreq": 42,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "سُبْحَانَ",
        "answer": "Glory be",
        "pcklId": "86",
        "rootWordId": 651,
        "tlit": "sub'ḥāna",
        "frequency": 92,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 29,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " قَالُوا سُبْحَانَ رَبِّنَا إِنَّا كُنَّا ظَالِمِينَ",
        "rootWord": "س ب ح",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "سُبْحَٰن",
        "waznEnglish": "floating",
        "waznTlit": "sub'ḥān",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 41,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "سَبِيلِهِ",
        "answer": "His way",
        "pcklId": "169",
        "rootWordId": 656,
        "tlit": "sabīlihi",
        "frequency": 176,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 7,
        "wordnum": 8,
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّ رَبَّكَ هُوَ أَعْلَمُ بِمَنْ ضَلَّ عَنْ سَبِيلِهِ وَهُوَ أَعْلَمُ بِالْمُهْتَدِينَ",
        "rootWord": "س ب ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "س ب ل",
        "waznEnglish": "(of) the way",
        "waznTlit": "sīn bā lām",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 176,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "السُّجُودِ",
        "answer": "prostrate",
        "pcklId": "37",
        "rootWordId": 659,
        "tlit": "l-sujūdi",
        "frequency": 92,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 42,
        "wordnum": 7,
        "arabicAyah": " يَوْمَ يُكْشَفُ عَنْ سَاقٍ وَيُدْعَوْنَ إِلَى السُّجُودِ فَلَا يَسْتَطِيعُونَ",
        "rootWord": "س ج د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "سُّجُود",
        "waznEnglish": "Prostrate",
        "waznTlit": "sujūd",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)",
        "waznFreq": 6,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "السُّجُودِ",
        "answer": "prostrate",
        "pcklId": "38",
        "rootWordId": 659,
        "tlit": "l-sujūdi",
        "frequency": 92,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 43,
        "wordnum": 9,
        "arabicAyah": " وَقَدْ كَانُوا يُدْعَوْنَ إِلَى السُّجُودِ وَهُمْ سَالِمُونَ",
        "rootWord": "س ج د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "سُّجُود",
        "waznEnglish": "Prostrate",
        "waznTlit": "sujūd",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)",
        "waznFreq": 6,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "يَسْطُرُونَ",
        "answer": "they write",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 688,
        "tlit": "yasṭurūna",
        "frequency": 16,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 1,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " ن وَالْقَلَمِ وَمَا يَسْطُرُونَ",
        "rootWord": "س ط ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "يَسْطُرُ",
        "waznEnglish": "to write",
        "waznTlit": "yasṭuru",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 1,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "أَسَاطِيرُ",
        "answer": "Stories",
        "pcklId": "8",
        "rootWordId": 688,
        "tlit": "asāṭīru",
        "frequency": 16,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 15,
        "wordnum": 6,
        "arabicAyah": " إِذَا تُتْلَىٰ عَلَيْهِ آيَاتُنَا قَالَ أَسَاطِيرُ الْأَوَّلِينَ",
        "rootWord": "س ط ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَسَٰطِير",
        "waznEnglish": "they write",
        "waznTlit": "asāṭīr",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 9,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "مِسْكِينٌ",
        "answer": "any poor person",
        "pcklId": "60",
        "rootWordId": 708,
        "tlit": "mis'kīnun",
        "frequency": 69,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 24,
        "wordnum": 6,
        "arabicAyah": " أَنْ لَا يَدْخُلَنَّهَا الْيَوْمَ عَلَيْكُمْ مِسْكِينٌ",
        "rootWord": "س ك ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مِسْكِين",
        "waznEnglish": "Dwell",
        "waznTlit": "mis'kīn",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)",
        "waznFreq": 23,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "سَالِمُونَ",
        "answer": "(were) sound",
        "pcklId": "82",
        "rootWordId": 718,
        "tlit": "sālimūna",
        "frequency": 140,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 43,
        "wordnum": 11,
        "arabicAyah": " وَقَدْ كَانُوا يُدْعَوْنَ إِلَى السُّجُودِ وَهُمْ سَالِمُونَ",
        "rootWord": "س ل م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "سَٰلِمُون",
        "waznEnglish": "you pay",
        "waznTlit": "sālimūn",
        "waznType": "Active participle",
        "waznFreq": 1,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الْمُسْلِمِينَ",
        "answer": "the Muslims",
        "pcklId": "133",
        "rootWordId": 718,
        "tlit": "l-mus'limīna",
        "frequency": 140,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 35,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " أَفَنَجْعَلُ الْمُسْلِمِينَ كَالْمُجْرِمِينَ",
        "rootWord": "س ل م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُسْلِم",
        "waznEnglish": "you pay",
        "waznTlit": "mus'lim",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form IV) (Proper noun)",
        "waznFreq": 39,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "سَمِعُوا",
        "answer": "they hear",
        "pcklId": "73",
        "rootWordId": 722,
        "tlit": "samiʿū",
        "frequency": 185,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 51,
        "wordnum": 8,
        "arabicAyah": " وَإِنْ يَكَادُ الَّذِينَ كَفَرُوا لَيُزْلِقُونَكَ بِأَبْصَارِهِمْ لَمَّا سَمِعُوا الذِّكْرَ",
        "rootWord": "س م ع",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "سَمِعَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to hear, to listen",
        "waznTlit": "samiʿa",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 78,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "سَاقٍ",
        "answer": "the shin",
        "pcklId": "8",
        "rootWordId": 744,
        "tlit": "sāqin",
        "frequency": 17,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 42,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " يَوْمَ يُكْشَفُ عَنْ سَاقٍ وَيُدْعَوْنَ إِلَى السُّجُودِ فَلَا يَسْتَطِيعُونَ",
        "rootWord": "س و ق",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "سَاق",
        "waznEnglish": "We drive them",
        "waznTlit": "sāq",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 4,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "شُرَكَاءُ",
        "answer": "partners",
        "pcklId": "115",
        "rootWordId": 771,
        "tlit": "shurakāu",
        "frequency": 168,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 41,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " أَمْ لَهُمْ شُرَكَاءُ فَلْيَأْتُوا بِشُرَكَائِهِمْ إِنْ كَانُوا صَادِقِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ش ر ك",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "شَرِيك",
        "waznEnglish": "and be a partner",
        "waznTlit": "sharīk",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 40,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "بِشُرَكَائِهِمْ",
        "answer": "their partners",
        "pcklId": "116",
        "rootWordId": 771,
        "tlit": "bishurakāihim",
        "frequency": 168,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 41,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " أَمْ لَهُمْ شُرَكَاءُ فَلْيَأْتُوا بِشُرَكَائِهِمْ إِنْ كَانُوا صَادِقِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ش ر ك",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "شَرِيك",
        "waznEnglish": "and be a partner",
        "waznTlit": "sharīk",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 40,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "فَأَصْبَحَتْ",
        "answer": "So it became",
        "pcklId": "28",
        "rootWordId": 817,
        "tlit": "fa-aṣbaḥat",
        "frequency": 45,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 20,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " فَأَصْبَحَتْ كَالصَّرِيمِ",
        "rootWord": "ص ب ح",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَصْبَحَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to become",
        "waznTlit": "aṣbaḥa",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)",
        "waznFreq": 28,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "مُصْبِحِينَ",
        "answer": "(in the) morning",
        "pcklId": "43",
        "rootWordId": 817,
        "tlit": "muṣ'biḥīna",
        "frequency": 45,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 17,
        "wordnum": 10,
        "arabicAyah": " إِذْ أَقْسَمُوا لَيَصْرِمُنَّهَا مُصْبِحِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ص ب ح",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُصْبِحِين",
        "waznEnglish": "seized them in the morning",
        "waznTlit": "muṣ'biḥīn",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form IV)",
        "waznFreq": 5,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "مُصْبِحِينَ",
        "answer": "(at) morning",
        "pcklId": "44",
        "rootWordId": 817,
        "tlit": "muṣ'biḥīna",
        "frequency": 45,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 21,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " فَتَنَادَوْا مُصْبِحِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ص ب ح",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُصْبِحِين",
        "waznEnglish": "seized them in the morning",
        "waznTlit": "muṣ'biḥīn",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form IV)",
        "waznFreq": 5,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "فَاصْبِرْ",
        "answer": "So be patient",
        "pcklId": "52",
        "rootWordId": 818,
        "tlit": "fa-iṣ'bir",
        "frequency": 103,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 48,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " فَاصْبِرْ لِحُكْمِ رَبِّكَ وَلَا تَكُنْ كَصَاحِبِ الْحُوتِ",
        "rootWord": "ص ب ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "صَبَرَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be patient",
        "waznTlit": "ṣabara",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 58,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "أَصْحَابَ",
        "answer": "(the) companions",
        "pcklId": "74",
        "rootWordId": 822,
        "tlit": "aṣḥāba",
        "frequency": 97,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 17,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّا بَلَوْنَاهُمْ كَمَا بَلَوْنَا أَصْحَابَ الْجَنَّةِ",
        "rootWord": "ص ح ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَصْحَٰب",
        "waznEnglish": "can be protected",
        "waznTlit": "aṣḥāb",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 78,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "كَصَاحِبِ",
        "answer": "like (the) companion",
        "pcklId": "89",
        "rootWordId": 822,
        "tlit": "kaṣāḥibi",
        "frequency": 97,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 48,
        "wordnum": 6,
        "arabicAyah": " فَاصْبِرْ لِحُكْمِ رَبِّكَ وَلَا تَكُنْ كَصَاحِبِ الْحُوتِ",
        "rootWord": "ص ح ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "صَاحِب",
        "waznEnglish": "can be protected",
        "waznTlit": "ṣāḥib",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 10,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "صَادِقِينَ",
        "answer": "truthful",
        "pcklId": "127",
        "rootWordId": 830,
        "tlit": "ṣādiqīna",
        "frequency": 155,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 41,
        "wordnum": 8,
        "arabicAyah": " أَمْ لَهُمْ شُرَكَاءُ فَلْيَأْتُوا بِشُرَكَائِهِمْ إِنْ كَانُوا صَادِقِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ص د ق",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "صَادِق",
        "waznEnglish": "are true",
        "waznTlit": "ṣādiq",
        "waznType": "Active participle",
        "waznFreq": 59,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "لَيَصْرِمُنَّهَا",
        "answer": "to pluck its fruit",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 839,
        "tlit": "layaṣrimunnahā",
        "frequency": 3,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 17,
        "wordnum": 9,
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّا بَلَوْنَاهُمْ كَمَا بَلَوْنَا أَصْحَابَ الْجَنَّةِ إِذْ أَقْسَمُوا لَيَصْرِمُنَّهَا مُصْبِحِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ص ر م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "يَصْرِمُ",
        "waznEnglish": "to pluck",
        "waznTlit": "yaṣrimu",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 1,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "كَالصَّرِيمِ",
        "answer": "as if reaped",
        "pcklId": "1",
        "rootWordId": 839,
        "tlit": "kal-ṣarīmi",
        "frequency": 3,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 20,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " فَأَصْبَحَتْ كَالصَّرِيمِ",
        "rootWord": "ص ر م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "صَّرِيم",
        "waznEnglish": "to pluck its fruit",
        "waznTlit": "ṣarīm",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 1,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "صَارِمِينَ",
        "answer": "pluck (the) fruit",
        "pcklId": "2",
        "rootWordId": 839,
        "tlit": "ṣārimīna",
        "frequency": 3,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 22,
        "wordnum": 7,
        "arabicAyah": " أَنِ اغْدُوا عَلَىٰ حَرْثِكُمْ إِنْ كُنْتُمْ صَارِمِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ص ر م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "صَٰرِمِين",
        "waznEnglish": "to pluck its fruit",
        "waznTlit": "ṣārimīn",
        "waznType": "Active participle",
        "waznFreq": 1,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الصَّالِحِينَ",
        "answer": "the righteous",
        "pcklId": "99",
        "rootWordId": 854,
        "tlit": "l-ṣāliḥīna",
        "frequency": 180,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 50,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " فَاجْتَبَاهُ رَبُّهُ فَجَعَلَهُ مِنَ الصَّالِحِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ص ل ح",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "صَٰلِح",
        "waznEnglish": "(were) righteous",
        "waznTlit": "ṣāliḥ",
        "waznType": "Active participle (Noun)",
        "waznFreq": 65,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "ضَلَّ",
        "answer": "has strayed",
        "pcklId": "52",
        "rootWordId": 891,
        "tlit": "ḍalla",
        "frequency": 191,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 7,
        "wordnum": 6,
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّ رَبَّكَ هُوَ أَعْلَمُ بِمَنْ ضَلَّ عَنْ سَبِيلِهِ وَهُوَ أَعْلَمُ بِالْمُهْتَدِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ض ل ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ضَلَّ",
        "waznEnglish": "to go astray, to err, to lose",
        "waznTlit": "ḍalla",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 53,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "لَضَالُّونَ",
        "answer": "(are) surely lost",
        "pcklId": "181",
        "rootWordId": 891,
        "tlit": "laḍāllūna",
        "frequency": 191,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 26,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " فَلَمَّا رَأَوْهَا قَالُوا إِنَّا لَضَالُّونَ",
        "rootWord": "ض ل ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ضَآلّ",
        "waznEnglish": "he went astray (from)",
        "waznTlit": "ḍāll",
        "waznType": "Active participle (Noun)",
        "waznFreq": 14,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "طَاغِينَ",
        "answer": "transgressors",
        "pcklId": "34",
        "rootWordId": 913,
        "tlit": "ṭāghīna",
        "frequency": 39,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 31,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " قَالُوا يَا وَيْلَنَا إِنَّا كُنَّا طَاغِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ط غ ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "طَٰغِين",
        "waznEnglish": "transgress",
        "waznTlit": "ṭāghīn",
        "waznType": "Active participle (Noun)",
        "waznFreq": 6,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "فَانْطَلَقُوا",
        "answer": "So they went",
        "pcklId": "16",
        "rootWordId": 921,
        "tlit": "fa-inṭalaqū",
        "frequency": 23,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 23,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " فَانْطَلَقُوا وَهُمْ يَتَخَافَتُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ط ل ق",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ٱنطَلَقَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to set out, to proceeed, to go forth",
        "waznTlit": "inṭalaqa",
        "waznType": "Verb (form VII)",
        "waznFreq": 9,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "تُطِعِ",
        "answer": "obey",
        "pcklId": "70",
        "rootWordId": 931,
        "tlit": "tuṭiʿi",
        "frequency": 129,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 8,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " فَلَا تُطِعِ الْمُكَذِّبِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ط و ع",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَطَاعَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to obey",
        "waznTlit": "aṭāʿa",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)",
        "waznFreq": 72,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "تُطِعْ",
        "answer": "obey",
        "pcklId": "71",
        "rootWordId": 931,
        "tlit": "tuṭiʿ",
        "frequency": 129,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 10,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَا تُطِعْ كُلَّ حَلَّافٍ مَهِينٍ",
        "rootWord": "ط و ع",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَطَاعَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to obey",
        "waznTlit": "aṭāʿa",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)",
        "waznFreq": 72,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "يَسْتَطِيعُونَ",
        "answer": "they will be able",
        "pcklId": "118",
        "rootWordId": 931,
        "tlit": "yastaṭīʿūna",
        "frequency": 129,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 42,
        "wordnum": 9,
        "arabicAyah": " يَوْمَ يُكْشَفُ عَنْ سَاقٍ وَيُدْعَوْنَ إِلَى السُّجُودِ فَلَا يَسْتَطِيعُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ط و ع",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ٱسْتَطَاعَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be able to, to be capable",
        "waznTlit": "is'taṭāʿa",
        "waznType": "Verb (form X)",
        "waznFreq": 42,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "فَطَافَ",
        "answer": "So there came",
        "pcklId": "5",
        "rootWordId": 932,
        "tlit": "faṭāfa",
        "frequency": 41,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 19,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " فَطَافَ عَلَيْهَا طَائِفٌ مِنْ رَبِّكَ وَهُمْ نَائِمُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ط و ف",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "طَافَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to circulate, to go around",
        "waznTlit": "ṭāfa",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 8,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "طَائِفٌ",
        "answer": "a visitation",
        "pcklId": "40",
        "rootWordId": 932,
        "tlit": "ṭāifun",
        "frequency": 41,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 19,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " فَطَافَ عَلَيْهَا طَائِفٌ مِنْ رَبِّكَ وَهُمْ نَائِمُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ط و ف",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "طَآئِف",
        "waznEnglish": "Will be circulated",
        "waznTlit": "ṭāif",
        "waznType": "Active participle",
        "waznFreq": 4,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "ظَالِمِينَ",
        "answer": "wrongdoers",
        "pcklId": "280",
        "rootWordId": 942,
        "tlit": "ẓālimīna",
        "frequency": 315,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 29,
        "wordnum": 6,
        "arabicAyah": " قَالُوا سُبْحَانَ رَبِّنَا إِنَّا كُنَّا ظَالِمِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ظ ل م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ظَالِم",
        "waznEnglish": "[you] have wronged",
        "waznTlit": "ẓālim",
        "waznType": "Active participle (Noun)",
        "waznFreq": 129,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "عُتُلٍّ",
        "answer": "Cruel",
        "pcklId": "1",
        "rootWordId": 955,
        "tlit": "ʿutullin",
        "frequency": 2,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 13,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " عُتُلٍّ بَعْدَ ذَٰلِكَ زَنِيمٍ",
        "rootWord": "ع ت ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عُتُلّ",
        "waznEnglish": "and drag him",
        "waznTlit": "ʿutull",
        "waznType": "Adjective",
        "waznFreq": 1,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "مُعْتَدٍ",
        "answer": "transgressor",
        "pcklId": "105",
        "rootWordId": 967,
        "tlit": "muʿ'tadin",
        "frequency": 106,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 12,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " مَنَّاعٍ لِلْخَيْرِ مُعْتَدٍ أَثِيمٍ",
        "rootWord": "ع د و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُعْتَد",
        "waznEnglish": "transgress",
        "waznTlit": "muʿ'tad",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form VIII) (Adjective)",
        "waznFreq": 3,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الْعَذَابُ",
        "answer": "(is) the punishment",
        "pcklId": "345",
        "rootWordId": 968,
        "tlit": "l-ʿadhābu",
        "frequency": 373,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 33,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " كَذَٰلِكَ الْعَذَابُ",
        "rootWord": "ع ذ ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَذَاب",
        "waznEnglish": "and He will punish",
        "waznTlit": "ʿadhāb",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 322,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "وَلَعَذَابُ",
        "answer": "And surely the punishment",
        "pcklId": "346",
        "rootWordId": 968,
        "tlit": "walaʿadhābu",
        "frequency": 373,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 33,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَعَذَابُ الْآخِرَةِ أَكْبَرُ لَوْ كَانُوا يَعْلَمُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ع ذ ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَذَاب",
        "waznEnglish": "and He will punish",
        "waznTlit": "ʿadhāb",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 322,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "بِالْعَرَاءِ",
        "answer": "onto (the) naked shore",
        "pcklId": "2",
        "rootWordId": 979,
        "tlit": "bil-ʿarāi",
        "frequency": 3,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 49,
        "wordnum": 8,
        "arabicAyah": " لَوْلَا أَنْ تَدَارَكَهُ نِعْمَةٌ مِنْ رَبِّهِ لَنُبِذَ بِالْعَرَاءِ وَهُوَ مَذْمُومٌ",
        "rootWord": "ع ر ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَرَآء",
        "waznEnglish": "you will be unclothed",
        "waznTlit": "ʿarā",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 2,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "عَسَىٰ",
        "answer": "Perhaps",
        "pcklId": "29",
        "rootWordId": 989,
        "tlit": "ʿasā",
        "frequency": 30,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 32,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " عَسَىٰ رَبُّنَا أَنْ يُبْدِلَنَا خَيْرًا مِنْهَا إِنَّا إِلَىٰ رَبِّنَا رَاغِبُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ع س ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ع س ي",
        "waznEnglish": "to perhaps",
        "waznTlit": "ʿayn sīn yā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 30,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "عَظِيمٍ",
        "answer": "great",
        "pcklId": "107",
        "rootWordId": 1005,
        "tlit": "ʿaẓīmin",
        "frequency": 128,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 4,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " وَإِنَّكَ لَعَلَىٰ خُلُقٍ عَظِيمٍ",
        "rootWord": "ع ظ م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَظِيم",
        "waznEnglish": "honors",
        "waznTlit": "ʿaẓīm",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Adjective)",
        "waznFreq": 120,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "يَعْلَمُونَ",
        "answer": "know",
        "pcklId": "359",
        "rootWordId": 1016,
        "tlit": "yaʿlamūna",
        "frequency": 854,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 33,
        "wordnum": 8,
        "arabicAyah": " كَذَٰلِكَ الْعَذَابُ وَلَعَذَابُ الْآخِرَةِ أَكْبَرُ لَوْ كَانُوا يَعْلَمُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ع ل م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَلِمَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to know",
        "waznTlit": "ʿalima",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 382,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "يَعْلَمُونَ",
        "answer": "they know",
        "pcklId": "360",
        "rootWordId": 1016,
        "tlit": "yaʿlamūna",
        "frequency": 854,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 44,
        "wordnum": 10,
        "arabicAyah": " سَنَسْتَدْرِجُهُمْ مِنْ حَيْثُ لَا يَعْلَمُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ع ل م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَلِمَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to know",
        "waznTlit": "ʿalima",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 382,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "أَعْلَمُ",
        "answer": "(is) most knowing",
        "pcklId": "457",
        "rootWordId": 1016,
        "tlit": "aʿlamu",
        "frequency": 854,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 7,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّ رَبَّكَ هُوَ أَعْلَمُ بِمَنْ ضَلَّ عَنْ سَبِيلِهِ",
        "rootWord": "ع ل م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَعْلَم",
        "waznEnglish": "they know",
        "waznTlit": "aʿlam",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)",
        "waznFreq": 49,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "أَعْلَمُ",
        "answer": "(is) most knowing",
        "pcklId": "458",
        "rootWordId": 1016,
        "tlit": "aʿlamu",
        "frequency": 854,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 7,
        "wordnum": 10,
        "arabicAyah": " وَهُوَ أَعْلَمُ بِالْمُهْتَدِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ع ل م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَعْلَم",
        "waznEnglish": "they know",
        "waznTlit": "aʿlam",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)",
        "waznFreq": 49,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "لِلْعَالَمِينَ",
        "answer": "to the worlds",
        "pcklId": "544",
        "rootWordId": 1016,
        "tlit": "lil'ʿālamīna",
        "frequency": 854,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 52,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " وَمَا هُوَ إِلَّا ذِكْرٌ لِلْعَالَمِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ع ل م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَٰلَمِين",
        "waznEnglish": "they know",
        "waznTlit": "ʿālamīn",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 73,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "عِنْدَ",
        "answer": "with",
        "pcklId": "154",
        "rootWordId": 1028,
        "tlit": "ʿinda",
        "frequency": 201,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 34,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّ لِلْمُتَّقِينَ عِنْدَ رَبِّهِمْ جَنَّاتِ النَّعِيمِ",
        "rootWord": "ع ن د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عِند",
        "waznEnglish": "with",
        "waznTlit": "ʿind",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Location adverb)",
        "waznFreq": 197,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "عِنْدَهُمُ",
        "answer": "(is) with them",
        "pcklId": "155",
        "rootWordId": 1028,
        "tlit": "ʿindahumu",
        "frequency": 201,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 47,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " أَمْ عِنْدَهُمُ الْغَيْبُ فَهُمْ يَكْتُبُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ع ن د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عِند",
        "waznEnglish": "with",
        "waznTlit": "ʿind",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Location adverb)",
        "waznFreq": 197,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "اغْدُوا",
        "answer": "Go early",
        "pcklId": "1",
        "rootWordId": 1053,
        "tlit": "igh'dū",
        "frequency": 16,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 22,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " أَنِ اغْدُوا عَلَىٰ حَرْثِكُمْ إِنْ كُنْتُمْ صَارِمِينَ",
        "rootWord": "غ د و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "غَدَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to leave early",
        "waznTlit": "ghada",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 3,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "وَغَدَوْا",
        "answer": "And they went early",
        "pcklId": "2",
        "rootWordId": 1053,
        "tlit": "waghadaw",
        "frequency": 16,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 25,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " وَغَدَوْا عَلَىٰ حَرْدٍ قَادِرِينَ",
        "rootWord": "غ د و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "غَدَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to leave early",
        "waznTlit": "ghada",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 3,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "مَغْرَمٍ",
        "answer": "(the) debt",
        "pcklId": "3",
        "rootWordId": 1058,
        "tlit": "maghramin",
        "frequency": 6,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 46,
        "wordnum": 6,
        "arabicAyah": " أَمْ تَسْأَلُهُمْ أَجْرًا فَهُمْ مِنْ مَغْرَمٍ مُثْقَلُونَ",
        "rootWord": "غ ر م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَّغْرَم",
        "waznEnglish": "inseparable",
        "waznTlit": "maghram",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 3,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الْغَيْبُ",
        "answer": "the unseen",
        "pcklId": "48",
        "rootWordId": 1093,
        "tlit": "l-ghaybu",
        "frequency": 60,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 47,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " أَمْ عِنْدَهُمُ الْغَيْبُ فَهُمْ يَكْتُبُونَ",
        "rootWord": "غ ي ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "غَيْب",
        "waznEnglish": "backbite",
        "waznTlit": "ghayb",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 49,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "غَيْرَ",
        "answer": "without",
        "pcklId": "144",
        "rootWordId": 1095,
        "tlit": "ghayra",
        "frequency": 154,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 3,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " وَإِنَّ لَكَ لَأَجْرًا غَيْرَ مَمْنُونٍ",
        "rootWord": "غ ي ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "غَيْر",
        "waznEnglish": "so they will surely change",
        "waznTlit": "ghayr",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)",
        "waznFreq": 147,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الْمَفْتُونُ",
        "answer": "(is) the afflicted one",
        "pcklId": "59",
        "rootWordId": 1105,
        "tlit": "l-maftūnu",
        "frequency": 60,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 6,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " بِأَيْيِكُمُ الْمَفْتُونُ",
        "rootWord": "ف ت ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَفْتُون",
        "waznEnglish": "(may) harm you",
        "waznTlit": "maftūn",
        "waznType": "Passive participle",
        "waznFreq": 1,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "فَأَقْبَلَ",
        "answer": "Then approached",
        "pcklId": "17",
        "rootWordId": 1174,
        "tlit": "fa-aqbala",
        "frequency": 294,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 30,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " فَأَقْبَلَ بَعْضُهُمْ عَلَىٰ بَعْضٍ يَتَلَاوَمُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ق ب ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَقْبَلَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to approach",
        "waznTlit": "aqbala",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)",
        "waznFreq": 9,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "قَادِرِينَ",
        "answer": "able",
        "pcklId": "116",
        "rootWordId": 1181,
        "tlit": "qādirīna",
        "frequency": 132,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 25,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " وَغَدَوْا عَلَىٰ حَرْدٍ قَادِرِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ق د ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَادِر",
        "waznEnglish": "they have control",
        "waznTlit": "qādir",
        "waznType": "Active participle",
        "waznFreq": 14,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "أَقْسَمُوا",
        "answer": "they swore",
        "pcklId": "15",
        "rootWordId": 1201,
        "tlit": "aqsamū",
        "frequency": 33,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 17,
        "wordnum": 8,
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّا بَلَوْنَاهُمْ كَمَا بَلَوْنَا أَصْحَابَ الْجَنَّةِ إِذْ أَقْسَمُوا لَيَصْرِمُنَّهَا مُصْبِحِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ق س م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَقْسَمُ",
        "waznEnglish": "to swear",
        "waznTlit": "aqsamu",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)",
        "waznFreq": 20,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "وَالْقَلَمِ",
        "answer": "By the pen",
        "pcklId": "2",
        "rootWordId": 1226,
        "tlit": "wal-qalami",
        "frequency": 4,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 1,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " ن وَالْقَلَمِ وَمَا يَسْطُرُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ق ل م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ق ل م",
        "waznEnglish": "their pens",
        "waznTlit": "qāf lām mīm",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 4,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "قَالَ",
        "answer": "he says",
        "pcklId": "1569",
        "rootWordId": 1245,
        "tlit": "qāla",
        "frequency": 1722,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 15,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " إِذَا تُتْلَىٰ عَلَيْهِ آيَاتُنَا قَالَ أَسَاطِيرُ الْأَوَّلِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ق و ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَالَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to say",
        "waznTlit": "qāla",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 1618,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "قَالُوا",
        "answer": "they said",
        "pcklId": "1570",
        "rootWordId": 1245,
        "tlit": "qālū",
        "frequency": 1722,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 26,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " فَلَمَّا رَأَوْهَا قَالُوا إِنَّا لَضَالُّونَ",
        "rootWord": "ق و ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَالَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to say",
        "waznTlit": "qāla",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 1618,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "قَالَ",
        "answer": "Said",
        "pcklId": "1571",
        "rootWordId": 1245,
        "tlit": "qāla",
        "frequency": 1722,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 28,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " قَالَ أَوْسَطُهُمْ أَلَمْ أَقُلْ لَكُمْ لَوْلَا تُسَبِّحُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ق و ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَالَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to say",
        "waznTlit": "qāla",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 1618,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "أَقُلْ",
        "answer": "I tell",
        "pcklId": "1572",
        "rootWordId": 1245,
        "tlit": "aqul",
        "frequency": 1722,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 28,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " قَالَ أَوْسَطُهُمْ أَلَمْ أَقُلْ لَكُمْ لَوْلَا تُسَبِّحُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ق و ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَالَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to say",
        "waznTlit": "qāla",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 1618,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "قَالُوا",
        "answer": "They said",
        "pcklId": "1573",
        "rootWordId": 1245,
        "tlit": "qālū",
        "frequency": 1722,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 29,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " قَالُوا سُبْحَانَ رَبِّنَا إِنَّا كُنَّا ظَالِمِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ق و ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَالَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to say",
        "waznTlit": "qāla",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 1618,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "قَالُوا",
        "answer": "They said",
        "pcklId": "1574",
        "rootWordId": 1245,
        "tlit": "qālū",
        "frequency": 1722,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 31,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " قَالُوا يَا وَيْلَنَا إِنَّا كُنَّا طَاغِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ق و ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَالَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to say",
        "waznTlit": "qāla",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 1618,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "وَيَقُولُونَ",
        "answer": "and they say",
        "pcklId": "1575",
        "rootWordId": 1245,
        "tlit": "wayaqūlūna",
        "frequency": 1722,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 51,
        "wordnum": 10,
        "arabicAyah": " وَيَقُولُونَ إِنَّهُ لَمَجْنُونٌ",
        "rootWord": "ق و ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَالَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to say",
        "waznTlit": "qāla",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 1618,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الْقِيَامَةِ",
        "answer": "(of) the Resurrection",
        "pcklId": "555",
        "rootWordId": 1246,
        "tlit": "l-qiyāmati",
        "frequency": 660,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 39,
        "wordnum": 8,
        "arabicAyah": " أَمْ لَكُمْ أَيْمَانٌ عَلَيْنَا بَالِغَةٌ إِلَىٰ يَوْمِ الْقِيَامَةِ",
        "rootWord": "ق و م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قِيَٰمَة",
        "waznEnglish": "they stand (still)",
        "waznTlit": "qiyāmat",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 70,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "أَكْبَرُ",
        "answer": "(is) greater",
        "pcklId": "67",
        "rootWordId": 1254,
        "tlit": "akbaru",
        "frequency": 161,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 33,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " كَذَٰلِكَ الْعَذَابُ وَلَعَذَابُ الْآخِرَةِ أَكْبَرُ لَوْ كَانُوا يَعْلَمُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ك ب ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَكْبَر",
        "waznEnglish": "they will grow up",
        "waznTlit": "akbar",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)",
        "waznFreq": 24,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "يَكْتُبُونَ",
        "answer": "write it",
        "pcklId": "48",
        "rootWordId": 1256,
        "tlit": "yaktubūna",
        "frequency": 319,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 47,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " أَمْ عِنْدَهُمُ الْغَيْبُ فَهُمْ يَكْتُبُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ك ت ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَتَبَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to write, to prescribe, to ordain",
        "waznTlit": "kataba",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 49,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "كِتَابٌ",
        "answer": "a book",
        "pcklId": "293",
        "rootWordId": 1256,
        "tlit": "kitābun",
        "frequency": 319,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 37,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " أَمْ لَكُمْ كِتَابٌ فِيهِ تَدْرُسُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ك ت ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كِتَٰب",
        "waznEnglish": "write",
        "waznTlit": "kitāb",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 260,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "يُكَذِّبُ",
        "answer": "denies",
        "pcklId": "168",
        "rootWordId": 1263,
        "tlit": "yukadhibu",
        "frequency": 282,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 44,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " فَذَرْنِي وَمَنْ يُكَذِّبُ بِهَٰذَا الْحَدِيثِ",
        "rootWord": "ك ذ ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَذَّبَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to deny, to reject",
        "waznTlit": "kadhaba",
        "waznType": "Verb (form II)",
        "waznFreq": 176,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الْمُكَذِّبِينَ",
        "answer": "the deniers",
        "pcklId": "268",
        "rootWordId": 1263,
        "tlit": "l-mukadhibīna",
        "frequency": 282,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 8,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " فَلَا تُطِعِ الْمُكَذِّبِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ك ذ ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُّكَذِّبِين",
        "waznEnglish": "[they] lie",
        "waznTlit": "mukadhibīn",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form II)",
        "waznFreq": 21,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "يُكْشَفُ",
        "answer": "will be uncovered",
        "pcklId": "13",
        "rootWordId": 1275,
        "tlit": "yuk'shafu",
        "frequency": 20,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 42,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " يَوْمَ يُكْشَفُ عَنْ سَاقٍ وَيُدْعَوْنَ إِلَى السُّجُودِ",
        "rootWord": "ك ش ف",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَشَفَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to remove, to uncover",
        "waznTlit": "kashafa",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 14,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "مَكْظُومٌ",
        "answer": "(was) distressed",
        "pcklId": "5",
        "rootWordId": 1276,
        "tlit": "makẓūmun",
        "frequency": 6,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 48,
        "wordnum": 11,
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَا تَكُنْ كَصَاحِبِ الْحُوتِ إِذْ نَادَىٰ وَهُوَ مَكْظُومٌ",
        "rootWord": "ك ظ م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَكْظُوم",
        "waznEnglish": "a suppressor",
        "waznTlit": "makẓūm",
        "waznType": "Passive participle",
        "waznFreq": 1,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "كَفَرُوا",
        "answer": "disbelieve",
        "pcklId": "279",
        "rootWordId": 1280,
        "tlit": "kafarū",
        "frequency": 525,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 51,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " وَإِنْ يَكَادُ الَّذِينَ كَفَرُوا لَيُزْلِقُونَكَ بِأَبْصَارِهِمْ",
        "rootWord": "ك ف ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَفَرَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to disbelieve",
        "waznTlit": "kafara",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 289,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "كُلَّ",
        "answer": "every",
        "pcklId": "347",
        "rootWordId": 1288,
        "tlit": "kulla",
        "frequency": 377,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 10,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَا تُطِعْ كُلَّ حَلَّافٍ مَهِينٍ",
        "rootWord": "ك ل ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كُلّ",
        "waznEnglish": "(is) a burden",
        "waznTlit": "kull",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)",
        "waznFreq": 359,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "يَكَادُ",
        "answer": "would almost",
        "pcklId": "22",
        "rootWordId": 1302,
        "tlit": "yakādu",
        "frequency": 24,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 51,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " وَإِنْ يَكَادُ الَّذِينَ كَفَرُوا لَيُزْلِقُونَكَ بِأَبْصَارِهِمْ لَمَّا سَمِعُوا الذِّكْرَ",
        "rootWord": "ك و د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ك و د",
        "waznEnglish": "to be near, to nearly do, to almost do",
        "waznTlit": "kāf wāw dāl",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 24,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "كَانَ",
        "answer": "(he) is",
        "pcklId": "1295",
        "rootWordId": 1305,
        "tlit": "kāna",
        "frequency": 1390,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 14,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " أَنْ كَانَ ذَا مَالٍ وَبَنِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ك و ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَانَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be",
        "waznTlit": "kāna",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 1358,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "كُنْتُمْ",
        "answer": "you would",
        "pcklId": "1296",
        "rootWordId": 1305,
        "tlit": "kuntum",
        "frequency": 1390,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 22,
        "wordnum": 6,
        "arabicAyah": " أَنِ اغْدُوا عَلَىٰ حَرْثِكُمْ إِنْ كُنْتُمْ صَارِمِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ك و ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَانَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be",
        "waznTlit": "kāna",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 1358,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "كُنَّا",
        "answer": "[we] were",
        "pcklId": "1297",
        "rootWordId": 1305,
        "tlit": "kunnā",
        "frequency": 1390,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 29,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " قَالُوا سُبْحَانَ رَبِّنَا إِنَّا كُنَّا ظَالِمِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ك و ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَانَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be",
        "waznTlit": "kāna",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 1358,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "كُنَّا",
        "answer": "[we] were",
        "pcklId": "1298",
        "rootWordId": 1305,
        "tlit": "kunnā",
        "frequency": 1390,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 31,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " قَالُوا يَا وَيْلَنَا إِنَّا كُنَّا طَاغِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ك و ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَانَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be",
        "waznTlit": "kāna",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 1358,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "كَانُوا",
        "answer": "they",
        "pcklId": "1299",
        "rootWordId": 1305,
        "tlit": "kānū",
        "frequency": 1390,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 33,
        "wordnum": 7,
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَعَذَابُ الْآخِرَةِ أَكْبَرُ لَوْ كَانُوا يَعْلَمُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ك و ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَانَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be",
        "waznTlit": "kāna",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 1358,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "كَانُوا",
        "answer": "they are",
        "pcklId": "1300",
        "rootWordId": 1305,
        "tlit": "kānū",
        "frequency": 1390,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 41,
        "wordnum": 7,
        "arabicAyah": " أَمْ لَهُمْ شُرَكَاءُ فَلْيَأْتُوا بِشُرَكَائِهِمْ إِنْ كَانُوا صَادِقِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ك و ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَانَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be",
        "waznTlit": "kāna",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 1358,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "كَانُوا",
        "answer": "they were",
        "pcklId": "1301",
        "rootWordId": 1305,
        "tlit": "kānū",
        "frequency": 1390,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 43,
        "wordnum": 6,
        "arabicAyah": " وَقَدْ كَانُوا يُدْعَوْنَ إِلَى السُّجُودِ وَهُمْ سَالِمُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ك و ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَانَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be",
        "waznTlit": "kāna",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 1358,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "تَكُنْ",
        "answer": "be",
        "pcklId": "1302",
        "rootWordId": 1305,
        "tlit": "takun",
        "frequency": 1390,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 48,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَا تَكُنْ كَصَاحِبِ الْحُوتِ إِذْ نَادَىٰ وَهُوَ مَكْظُومٌ",
        "rootWord": "ك و ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَانَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be",
        "waznTlit": "kāna",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 1358,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "كَيْدِي",
        "answer": "My plan",
        "pcklId": "29",
        "rootWordId": 1307,
        "tlit": "kaydī",
        "frequency": 35,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 45,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " وَأُمْلِي لَهُمْ إِنَّ كَيْدِي مَتِينٌ",
        "rootWord": "ك ي د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَيْد",
        "waznEnglish": "scheme against me",
        "waznTlit": "kayd",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 26,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "كَيْفَ",
        "answer": "How",
        "pcklId": "69",
        "rootWordId": 1308,
        "tlit": "kayfa",
        "frequency": 83,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 36,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " مَا لَكُمْ كَيْفَ تَحْكُمُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ك ي ف",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ك ي ف",
        "waznEnglish": "How",
        "waznTlit": "kāf yā fā",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Interogative particle)",
        "waznFreq": 83,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "يَتَلَاوَمُونَ",
        "answer": "blaming each other",
        "pcklId": "3",
        "rootWordId": 1359,
        "tlit": "yatalāwamūna",
        "frequency": 14,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 30,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " فَأَقْبَلَ بَعْضُهُمْ عَلَىٰ بَعْضٍ يَتَلَاوَمُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ل و م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "يَتَلَٰوَمُ",
        "waznEnglish": "to blame",
        "waznTlit": "yatalāwamu",
        "waznType": "Verb (form VI)",
        "waznFreq": 1,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "مَتِينٌ",
        "answer": "(is) firm",
        "pcklId": "1",
        "rootWordId": 1368,
        "tlit": "matīnun",
        "frequency": 3,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 45,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " وَأُمْلِي لَهُمْ إِنَّ كَيْدِي مَتِينٌ",
        "rootWord": "م ت ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "م ت ن",
        "waznEnglish": "(is) firm",
        "waznTlit": "mīm tā nūn",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)",
        "waznFreq": 3,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "مَشَّاءٍ",
        "answer": "going about",
        "pcklId": "21",
        "rootWordId": 1398,
        "tlit": "mashāin",
        "frequency": 23,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 11,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " هَمَّازٍ مَشَّاءٍ بِنَمِيمٍ",
        "rootWord": "م ش ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَّشَّآء",
        "waznEnglish": "they walk",
        "waznTlit": "mashā",
        "waznType": "Adjective",
        "waznFreq": 1,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "وَأُمْلِي",
        "answer": "And I will give respite",
        "pcklId": "8",
        "rootWordId": 1417,
        "tlit": "wa-um'lī",
        "frequency": 10,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 45,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " وَأُمْلِي لَهُمْ إِنَّ كَيْدِي مَتِينٌ",
        "rootWord": "م ل و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَمْلَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to give respite",
        "waznTlit": "amlā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)",
        "waznFreq": 9,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "مَنَّاعٍ",
        "answer": "A preventer",
        "pcklId": "13",
        "rootWordId": 1418,
        "tlit": "mannāʿin",
        "frequency": 17,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 12,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " مَنَّاعٍ لِلْخَيْرِ مُعْتَدٍ أَثِيمٍ",
        "rootWord": "م ن ع",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَّنَّاع",
        "waznEnglish": "prevents",
        "waznTlit": "mannāʿ",
        "waznType": "Adjective",
        "waznFreq": 2,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "مَمْنُونٍ",
        "answer": "end",
        "pcklId": "24",
        "rootWordId": 1419,
        "tlit": "mamnūnin",
        "frequency": 27,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 3,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " وَإِنَّ لَكَ لَأَجْرًا غَيْرَ مَمْنُونٍ",
        "rootWord": "م ن ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَمْنُون",
        "waznEnglish": "bestowed a Favor",
        "waznTlit": "mamnūn",
        "waznType": "Passive participle",
        "waznFreq": 4,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "مَهِينٍ",
        "answer": "worthless",
        "pcklId": "1",
        "rootWordId": 1423,
        "tlit": "mahīnin",
        "frequency": 4,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 10,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَا تُطِعْ كُلَّ حَلَّافٍ مَهِينٍ",
        "rootWord": "م ه ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "م ه ن",
        "waznEnglish": "despised",
        "waznTlit": "mīm hā nūn",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Adjective)",
        "waznFreq": 4,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "مَالٍ",
        "answer": "(of) wealth",
        "pcklId": "73",
        "rootWordId": 1427,
        "tlit": "mālin",
        "frequency": 86,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 14,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " أَنْ كَانَ ذَا مَالٍ وَبَنِينَ",
        "rootWord": "م و ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "م و ل",
        "waznEnglish": "[the] wealth",
        "waznTlit": "mīm wāw lām",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 86,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "لَنُبِذَ",
        "answer": "surely he would have been thrown",
        "pcklId": "8",
        "rootWordId": 1436,
        "tlit": "lanubidha",
        "frequency": 12,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 49,
        "wordnum": 7,
        "arabicAyah": " لَوْلَا أَنْ تَدَارَكَهُ نِعْمَةٌ مِنْ رَبِّهِ لَنُبِذَ بِالْعَرَاءِ وَهُوَ مَذْمُومٌ",
        "rootWord": "ن ب ذ",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نَبَذَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to throw, to cast",
        "waznTlit": "nabadha",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 10,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "فَتَنَادَوْا",
        "answer": "And they called one another",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 1455,
        "tlit": "fatanādaw",
        "frequency": 53,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 21,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " فَتَنَادَوْا مُصْبِحِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ن د و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "تَنَادَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to call",
        "waznTlit": "tanāda",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 1,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "نَادَىٰ",
        "answer": "he called out",
        "pcklId": "42",
        "rootWordId": 1455,
        "tlit": "nādā",
        "frequency": 53,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 48,
        "wordnum": 9,
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَا تَكُنْ كَصَاحِبِ الْحُوتِ إِذْ نَادَىٰ وَهُوَ مَكْظُومٌ",
        "rootWord": "ن د و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نَادَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to call",
        "waznTlit": "nādā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form III)",
        "waznFreq": 44,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "بِنِعْمَةِ",
        "answer": "by (the) Grace",
        "pcklId": "116",
        "rootWordId": 1492,
        "tlit": "biniʿ'mati",
        "frequency": 140,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 2,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " مَا أَنْتَ بِنِعْمَةِ رَبِّكَ بِمَجْنُونٍ",
        "rootWord": "ن ع م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نِعْمَة",
        "waznEnglish": "then good",
        "waznTlit": "niʿ'mat",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 50,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "نِعْمَةٌ",
        "answer": "a Favor",
        "pcklId": "117",
        "rootWordId": 1492,
        "tlit": "niʿ'matun",
        "frequency": 140,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 49,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " لَوْلَا أَنْ تَدَارَكَهُ نِعْمَةٌ مِنْ رَبِّهِ لَنُبِذَ بِالْعَرَاءِ وَهُوَ مَذْمُومٌ",
        "rootWord": "ن ع م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نِعْمَة",
        "waznEnglish": "then good",
        "waznTlit": "niʿ'mat",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 50,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "النَّعِيمِ",
        "answer": "(of) Delight",
        "pcklId": "132",
        "rootWordId": 1492,
        "tlit": "l-naʿīmi",
        "frequency": 140,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 34,
        "wordnum": 6,
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّ لِلْمُتَّقِينَ عِنْدَ رَبِّهِمْ جَنَّاتِ النَّعِيمِ",
        "rootWord": "ن ع م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نَعِيم",
        "waznEnglish": "then good",
        "waznTlit": "naʿīm",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 17,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "بِنَمِيمٍ",
        "answer": "with malicious gossip",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 1523,
        "tlit": "binamīmin",
        "frequency": 1,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 11,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " هَمَّازٍ مَشَّاءٍ بِنَمِيمٍ",
        "rootWord": "ن م م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ن م م",
        "waznEnglish": "with malicious gossip",
        "waznTlit": "nūn mīm mīm",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 1,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "نَائِمُونَ",
        "answer": "were asleep",
        "pcklId": "8",
        "rootWordId": 1534,
        "tlit": "nāimūna",
        "frequency": 9,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 19,
        "wordnum": 7,
        "arabicAyah": " فَطَافَ عَلَيْهَا طَائِفٌ مِنْ رَبِّكَ وَهُمْ نَائِمُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ن و م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نَآئِمُون",
        "waznEnglish": "your dream",
        "waznTlit": "nāimūn",
        "waznType": "Active participle",
        "waznFreq": 2,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "بِالْمُهْتَدِينَ",
        "answer": "of the guided ones",
        "pcklId": "314",
        "rootWordId": 1547,
        "tlit": "bil-muh'tadīna",
        "frequency": 316,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 7,
        "wordnum": 11,
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّ رَبَّكَ هُوَ أَعْلَمُ بِمَنْ ضَلَّ عَنْ سَبِيلِهِ وَهُوَ أَعْلَمُ بِالْمُهْتَدِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ه د ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُّهْتَدُون",
        "waznEnglish": "Guide us",
        "waznTlit": "muh'tadūn",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form VIII)",
        "waznFreq": 17,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "هَمَّازٍ",
        "answer": "Defamer",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 1563,
        "tlit": "hammāzin",
        "frequency": 3,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 11,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " هَمَّازٍ مَشَّاءٍ بِنَمِيمٍ",
        "rootWord": "ه م ز",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "هَمَّاز",
        "waznEnglish": "Defamer",
        "waznTlit": "hammāz",
        "waznType": "Adjective",
        "waznFreq": 1,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "وَدُّوا",
        "answer": "They wish",
        "pcklId": "15",
        "rootWordId": 1596,
        "tlit": "waddū",
        "frequency": 29,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 9,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " وَدُّوا لَوْ تُدْهِنُ فَيُدْهِنُونَ",
        "rootWord": "و د د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "وَدَّ",
        "waznEnglish": "to love, to wish",
        "waznTlit": "wadda",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 17,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "فَذَرْنِي",
        "answer": "So leave Me",
        "pcklId": "34",
        "rootWordId": 1600,
        "tlit": "fadharnī",
        "frequency": 45,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 44,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " فَذَرْنِي وَمَنْ يُكَذِّبُ بِهَٰذَا الْحَدِيثِ",
        "rootWord": "و ذ ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "و ذ ر",
        "waznEnglish": "to leave, to forsake",
        "waznTlit": "wāw dhāl rā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 45,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "أَوْسَطُهُمْ",
        "answer": "(the) most moderate of them",
        "pcklId": "2",
        "rootWordId": 1608,
        "tlit": "awsaṭuhum",
        "frequency": 5,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 28,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " قَالَ أَوْسَطُهُمْ أَلَمْ أَقُلْ لَكُمْ لَوْلَا تُسَبِّحُونَ",
        "rootWord": "و س ط",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَوْسَط",
        "waznEnglish": "Then penetrate (in the) center",
        "waznTlit": "awsaṭ",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 2,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "سَنَسِمُهُ",
        "answer": "We will brand him",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 1612,
        "tlit": "sanasimuhu",
        "frequency": 2,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 16,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " سَنَسِمُهُ عَلَى الْخُرْطُومِ",
        "rootWord": "و س م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نَسِمُ",
        "waznEnglish": "to brand",
        "waznTlit": "nasimu",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 1,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "لِلْمُتَّقِينَ",
        "answer": "for the righteous",
        "pcklId": "254",
        "rootWordId": 1641,
        "tlit": "lil'muttaqīna",
        "frequency": 258,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 34,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّ لِلْمُتَّقِينَ عِنْدَ رَبِّهِمْ جَنَّاتِ النَّعِيمِ",
        "rootWord": "و ق ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُتَّقِين",
        "waznEnglish": "and save us",
        "waznTlit": "muttaqīn",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form VIII)",
        "waznFreq": 49,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "أَيْمَانٌ",
        "answer": "oaths",
        "pcklId": "64",
        "rootWordId": 1662,
        "tlit": "aymānun",
        "frequency": 71,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 39,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " أَمْ لَكُمْ أَيْمَانٌ عَلَيْنَا بَالِغَةٌ إِلَىٰ يَوْمِ الْقِيَامَةِ إِنَّ لَكُمْ لَمَا تَحْكُمُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ي م ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "يَمِين",
        "waznEnglish": "the right",
        "waznTlit": "yamīn",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 65,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "يَوْمِ",
        "answer": "(the) Day",
        "pcklId": "293",
        "rootWordId": 1664,
        "tlit": "yawmi",
        "frequency": 405,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 39,
        "wordnum": 7,
        "arabicAyah": " أَمْ لَكُمْ أَيْمَانٌ عَلَيْنَا بَالِغَةٌ إِلَىٰ يَوْمِ الْقِيَامَةِ إِنَّ لَكُمْ لَمَا تَحْكُمُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ي و م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ي و م",
        "waznEnglish": "(of the) Day",
        "waznTlit": "yā wāw mīm",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)",
        "waznFreq": 405,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الْيَوْمَ",
        "answer": "today",
        "pcklId": "389",
        "rootWordId": 1664,
        "tlit": "l-yawma",
        "frequency": 405,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 24,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " أَنْ لَا يَدْخُلَنَّهَا الْيَوْمَ عَلَيْكُمْ مِسْكِينٌ",
        "rootWord": "ي و م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ي و م",
        "waznEnglish": "(of the) Day",
        "waznTlit": "yā wāw mīm",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Time adverb)",
        "waznFreq": 405,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "يَوْمَ",
        "answer": "(The) Day",
        "pcklId": "390",
        "rootWordId": 1664,
        "tlit": "yawma",
        "frequency": 405,
        "surahnum": 68,
        "ayahnum": 42,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " يَوْمَ يُكْشَفُ عَنْ سَاقٍ وَيُدْعَوْنَ إِلَى السُّجُودِ فَلَا يَسْتَطِيعُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ي و م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ي و م",
        "waznEnglish": "(of the) Day",
        "waznTlit": "yā wāw mīm",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Time adverb)",
        "waznFreq": 405,
        "hasRootWord": true
    }
]; 
export default words;